<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Python and R</title>
      <link>/blog/an-introduction-to-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/an-introduction-to-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to data science, there has been a debate between Python and R languages that I have recently learned about. Although I prefer to use R, both Python and R are generally useful and helpful for coding. However, each has their own advantages and disadvantages.
For instance, Python generally has a more simplified syntax (ex. has less braces and parentheses) and is more popularly used among people. On the other hand, R offers more easily accessible packages and is used more often by those specifically in the field of biostats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis Finding Data I chose to use the datasets, trump_approval_trend and trump_approval_poll, because I was curious and wanted to see the percentage of those who approve or disapprove of President Trump. Additionally, I wanted to see the differences and similarities between the two datasets in terms of estimate and actual rating. The trump_approval_trend has 11 variables and 1044 rows, and the trump_approval_poll has 20 variables and 3051 rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting Introducing Dataset I chose a different dataset from my project 1 because I ran into a lot of knitting issues with project 1 and wanted to try a different dataset. For project 2, I used the package fivethirtyeight and chose dataset, police_killings, that analyzes where police have killed Americans in the year of 2015. I chose this dataset because I wanted to see if there were any trends with killings of individuals to their relevant location and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>